If you're an online coach, chances
are that you're a fucking hypocrite.
Now, [chuckles] no offense, but if you
and I have anything in common,
it's probably
that we're really good at giving advice
that we don't really listen to ourselves.
The first thing I'm going to call you out
on is this 10K month, the buckle.
If you're a 2K, 3K, 4K, 5K a month,
10K a month is pretty fucking
stupid, and I'll explain why.
How many times have you had a client come
to you,
let's say you're a weight loss coach,
because you could be coaching people all
kinds of different things. "Hey,
I really want to lose 10 kilograms."
And you go,
"Shut up. You don't.
You want to lose one kilogram,
and you want to lose it 10
times." And they go, "Wow,
that's actually such an interesting way to
put it." You
go, "Yeah.
We just aim for one kilogram because we
could lose that in a couple of
weeks, and then we can celebrate,
and then we can aim for the next one.
If you wait until you reach 10 kilograms
of weight loss, we could be a year away
from being able to celebrate,
and that's not good for motivation." Yet
the same
advice falls flat yourself.
You might not even be halfway to 10K,
and that's a
problem. Now, in this video,
I'm going to talk to you about how long it
takes, the
online/offline journey, the mistakes
that I made, the market
saturation/oversaturation,
what social medias to use, whether
or not you need to go
viral, turning viewers into buyers,
how much do you charge,
how do you structure
it, et cetera. We're going to get into it,
okay?
Because my name's James Smith,
and I'm old.
Back in my day,
people used to use Facebook.
I've learned a lot.
I'm going to share it with you now.
But let's get out of this setting
and get into
the nitty-gritty for a second, all right?
Oh,
there will be a link in the description to
my PT Starter Kit.
It's a couple hundred US dollars.
It's not a lot.
I've actually made it cheaper than it
needs to be because it's your way into my
ecosystem. You shouldn't trust me,
but that is my equivalent of sticking the
tip in
just to see how it feels,
and then move on. Anyway,
let's get into it.
I can now technically say
that I've worked with over 1,000 fitness
businesses, and
if I say that,
you should feel sorry for me.
Look,
there's nothing wrong with you fitness
coaches, but thank you for the car,
but you're hard work.
The first question is,
how long does it take?
Now, rough timeline.
Became a personal trainer in 2014.
Got my first online client end of 2016,
probably 2017.
So, you're looking about three years.
Nowadays, it's not going to take you
that long because back in the day
when I said
I was an online coach,
people looked at me like I said to them
that I was an online
plumber. But I would say conservatively,
let's say three to six months to
reach 50% cap. And I'm so old
that cap means to me capacity, not
whether or not I'm lying.
And this kind of gets us into our next
question about,
are we offline or online?
Even conservatively three to six months,
whatever
coach you are, physio,
could be a breathwork coach,
could be a personal trainer,
whatever it is,
we probably want to have some in-person
clients.
Now, there are pros and cons to each one.
In person,
a lot easier to acquire clients.
You could be able to get someone through
the door in a very short period of time.
Online, a little bit harder. Online,
a lot easier to scale.
In person,
you are limited to the amount of time.
Say you're charging, I don't know,
35 pounds or $40 an hour.
You're going to have to give them the
hour. Online, you can sell a result.
In person,
although you can sell the result,
you're still going to be selling your
time a little bit.
But that's just the game.
And just before we get into the capacity
thing, let's look at this.
Let's imagine we have months. In reality,
it's probably going to look like this,
because you're going to build up your
capacity.
You're going to take on your first bit of
online clients.
So, what I'm showing you here
is you're going to start in person,
not have any
online clients.
You're just going to be pumping content.
Then you're going to get to probably like
half capacity, probably still not have
any online clients. Then it's
when you get to full capacity in person,
we're
probably going to see the shift
that you start taking on some clients.
Then when you're full
and you're starting to pick up a bit of
momentum, that's when
we're going to have to drop in-person to
do online.
And that's just because this
is more scalable.
Then there's going to get a point
that you're going to minimize the amount
of
in-person you're doing.
Everyone at the gym's going to think
you're crazy, but it's
really because you've got loads of people
online doing work with you.
Now, keep in mind, if I
was really a charlatan,
I would lie to you right now and
go,
"You can get your first client in 40 days
and be fully booked and
move to Bali," and whatever bollocks it
is they're fucking teaching you.
And again, most business mentors that
are out there on YouTube, I watch their
content. Not to get educated.
I'm a spiteful prick,
and I just love going and
seeing how bad the advice is
that they're giving.
None of them have built
or scaled an online business.
They've made their money from doing what
I'm doing here. Okay.
How many clients can you have?
Good question. No one asked it.
I'm just fucking psychic. In person, 30.
Online, 50.
The reason I say 30,
we're going to aim for a utopian world
where you only
work five days a week,
and out of those five days,
you're doing six hours.
Ideally, between 6:00 a.m. and 2:00 p.m.,
because if you're going to get to work at
6:00 a.m., this is the thing
that people don't realize.
So, let's look at people
that work in an office.
They get to work at 9:00 a.m.
They leave at 5:00, 5:30. So,
if you're going to arrive at the office
three hours
before that,
you should be able to leave three hours
before.
Staying in the gym after 2:00, 3:00 p.m.,
yeah, sure, if you're in your first three
to six months,
but that's something you need to eradicate
real quick.
Now,
the reason you can take more clients
online is they just take up less time.
Now,
why do we set caps on the amount of
clients that we've got?
Well, this brings us into commodity.
As you've probably seen, this
is a 911 GT3.
Now, if I go into the dealership,
I can't just buy this car.
They limit the amount they make,
which makes them bloody expensive.
Now, I paid a small fortune for this car.
But the guy who had it before me paid even
less.
So, a quick one-minute recap here.
Once you buy loads of cars from Porsche,
they put you on a list, same as Rolex.
Once you've bought a few watches from
Rolex, you're on the list.
And when they get a new allocation of
watches, because they trust you,
they give it
to you. Because these are commoditized,
and so are Rolexes and APs and Pateks,
they need to have an element of trust so
that when you buy it, you're not just
going to flip it. So, for instance,
one of the reasons I wouldn't probably be
able
to get a GT3 RS from retail is
that I could buy it from Porsche,
go down the
street to a garage,
and sell it for 100K more than what I just
bought it for.
Same with Rolex.
If they sell me a Rolex Submariner,
Day-Date, whatever,
if I go down the road to a jeweler's,
I can sell it at a markup.
Because it's commoditized. There
is a certain amount of demand for it.
That's why on the gray market,
even though I got this from Porsche,
I probably paid
100K over the list price for the GT3
because of the amount
of people that want one.
The reason I paid that money for it,
and the reason they
charge that, is because they can.
The demand is there.
Demand's a very, very important word.
Now, there is no demand
if you say yes to everyone.
So, by limiting the amount of people
that you have online,
you can get yourselves
into this paradigm. You
are never in two places at the same
time.
You are either raising your prices
or you're marketing harder.
So, if you are full
and you're at your capacity,
you should raise your prices so
that you're not full anymore. And
if you're not in a position to raise
prices
because you're not at capacity,
you should market yourself harder.
So, my business mentorship,
which I'll also put a link to in the
description,
started at 800 US dollars,
and now it's at 3,500 because the demand
has grown.
My YouTube's grown. My Instagram's grown.
Also,
the perception in the industry's grown.
It's probably going to grow a lot more.
We're about to announce a raise
that we're doing.
For any of you new to my channel,
I'm a co-founder of a business
Called Nutonic. And we do energy drinks,
we do focus
pouches,
and you're going to find out next week
that we've just been valued at $60
million. So that's cool. So you
are forever living in this world of
raising prices and marketing harder.
It's like why I can't stand some of my
mates have spare time and they're broke.
I'm like, "Well, why don't you use
that spare time to just market harder?" So
for
instance, if my sales
are down a little bit in the mentorship,
do you know what I
do?
I double the output of YouTube videos
or double the output of short-form
content.
I double the output of email marketing.
Marketing harder is just doing more.
Sending more emails, sending more offers.
Now, what mistakes did I make
when I began?
First one is I didn't take this advice on
board, and I remember one
day doing 14 hours of PT in a day,
and I came home and I
was a shell of a human.
And overworking yourself makes you
depressed.
And when you're depressed,
you experience nihilism and you think,
"What am I even
doing this for?" And that
is not good for motivation.
You are better off charging more,
having less clients,
than being in a state of
panic. So let me just make this clear.
Panic beats overwhelm.
Let me do that one more time.
I would rather that you
were panicking that you
didn't have enough clients than you
are overworked and overwhelmed with the
amount
of work you're doing. For instance,
my barber, he said, "Well,
if I raise prices, I
might lose a few clients." I said,
"Good." I said,
"Do you know what you need?"
Because he's always overworked
and he undercharges,
and he's always fucking busy.
I said,
"I could do with you staring at an empty
barber's chair for a little bit."
I said, "Tesh,
do you know what would be good for you?
Having to stare at a fucking empty seat
for two hours a day." Because guess what?
That changes a man. That changes a woman.
For those of you that haven't got clients,
go sit at your fucking laptop with no
one to work with, and then the panic
that comes is a great panic.
For instance, here's another example.
Every time I've spent a heinous amount of
money, I've experienced panic that then
makes me earn more money.
And the reason is
that I'm so anxious about all the
money that I spent
that I have no other options
but to make more.
It's a race to the bottom.
Overworking yourself,
that's what I'm trying to say.
Again, my PT starter kit
is linked in the description.
You should buy it because even this
advice, I'm saving you so many fucking
headaches.
You should just buy the course
and do nothing with it.
It's like a donation. GoFundMe.
GoFundMe car collection.
Another thing,
so I'll be honest with you whilst we're
here.
The GT3 RS doesn't come in a manual,
and everyone's like, "PDK is quicker."
I'm not a Formula 1 driver,
and what I've come to realize is,
doing a lot of track
days, I'm not even
that good at driving around a racetrack.
I'm all right.
I'm above average. But I'm not all that.
But also, if I get the GT3 RS,
you get the magnesium wheels.
If I ding one of those,
that'll be a fucking headache.
The tires on this cost about 500 pounds
each, which is quite a lot, don't get me
wrong. But if I'm to get a Lamborghini,
if I'm to get a Huracán or an
Aventador SVJ, anything like that,
the tires, you
have to get a special Lamborghini tire
that has an L on it, and it's double the
price, if not more, and your warranty
is voided if you put cheap tires on it.
So if you don't get the rip-off tires from
Lamborghini and you crash, they'll go,
"Oh,
you had the wrong tires on it." Warranty.
Anyway, it's bollocks.
That is the perfect car because I can
daily it. I just love it.
I've really missed it.
I've been in Japan for two weeks.
I've missed you.
So yeah, give me your fucking money.
Okay,
the next objection you probably have
is the fitness industry being
oversaturated. And you know what?
In some respects it is.
The one thing you don't want to do
is be a carbon cutout of everyone else
that's
online. And so many people,
"If you've struggled to lose fat
or build muscle, then
I've got a solution." You just got to
stand out from the crowd.
And now the landscape's changing,
you've just got to adapt to it.
Through history and evolution,
any animal that expects the environment to
adapt
for it dies out. The animals
that adapt to the environment survive.
Any of you that have read "Sapiens" should
know that.
So for instance,
some of you now should be looking at the
market and going, "Okay,
where's the space?
Is it with GLP-1 medications?
Is it focusing on training?
Is it being sport specific?
Am I going to get into..." Whatever it is.
The majority of fitness coaches online,
it's a bit like the blind leading the
blind,
and they do struggle to build a personal
brand.
So for instance,
if someone made a video
and came out F'n and blinding, "Oh, it's
like that." Someone could be like, "Oh,
you made a video like James Smith,"
because
I got to own that space.
And for so many of you in the fitness
industry, you get to
create space and own it as long as you do
have a sense of
individualism. Now,
a lot of people out there are telling you,
you need to go
viral. I would disagree.
I actually think
that you need to make videos that
solve people's problems. So for instance,
in this video, I reckon I need to get you
five times.
I reckon there has to be five instances
where you go, "Oh, never really
thought about it like that before."
That could be one.
Two could be like, "Fucking hell.
I've always thought that,
but no one's ever put
it into words." Number three could be
like, "I'm so glad he said that." Number
four could be like, "Do you know what?
I'm going to do that right away." Number
four might even be the time where you
pause the video, go to WhatsApp,
message some people about some stuff.
You're like, "Hey, Trevor,
meet me at the gym tomorrow.
Me and you are making some fitness
content." Then you come back to the video.
That's four.
Then number five could be like, "Cor,
I wonder what I get if I pay
him." You need to have probably five of
those.
Hopefully, I'll get five in this,
so I help your ability to give me money.
I help your build my car collection.
But to be honest,
I banner about the car collection.
I actually will need a bigger house.
But I love my house, so I'm in a conflict.
Spent like 20 grand making my driveway
bigger.
If I get another car,
it'll be like musical chairs every time I
want to drive.
And the Lambo tire thing kills me a little
bit, but maybe that's just a sign of not
earning enough money. I don't know. Oh,
yeah. Viral fitness content.
So instead of trying to go viral, try
and solve loads of problems.
And the best way you can do this
is a little exercise for you.
From today, write down 20 problems
that your in-person clients are
facing. Solve them. How can I make
that a video?
Now, the one thing I'd do on that
is really, really think about the hook.
The first thing that you're saying.
So for instance,
the hook in this video is,
I believe I called you a fucking
hypocrite. And the reason that I did
that is, one, it's unique to me,
and not many
people could get away with it, and two,
it kind of took you back a bit.
Then I used an analogy of how you're a
hypocrite because you don't take the
advice
that you give people,
and hopefully I would've given you an
emotive response to get
you there.
So once you've got those problems,
think about a hook, some kind of
emotive response you could get out of
someone, maybe a proper analogy.
Remember,
adults are very much like children,
and when you talk to them, they don't
really listen. But if you're like, "Wow,
look what I have here.
This right here represents the problems
that you face."
You know what I mean?
You give them something, they're like,
"Wow. Wow Oh, wow.
Yeah, you get it. Now, this
is the framework.
You would've heard me call this the four
S's.
Basically, we've got socials,
we've got squeeze,
we get their email address, we've
got solve, and we've got scale,
but we're not going to call it that.
We have views at the top. Cool, good.
They pretty much are a determinant of how
good your content is.
But if you threw your cat out a window
and it got loads of views, that's not what
I'm talking about. I'm talking about
if solving problems gets you good views.
So if you're getting loads of views on
maybe a cookbook, you then do your squeeze
page,
and you can get loads of people's data,
you get email addresses.
Maybe you're doing it on rep ranges
and you do an RPE calculator.
Maybe you're doing it on fat loss,
you get people on your calorie calculator
or
whatever it is.
The next thing you do with the data
is you send offers.
That's what marketing emails are.
You're sending people offers.
Now,
if someone responds to your offer by
clicking, they visit.
So they'd be visiting your landing page,
let's say. Then visits.
If you get a certain amount of buyers,
then we can look into...
That looks like it says gaze.
It means buyers.
Then we have retention, and we have GOATs.
The reason I'm saying
is you've done all this work to get
someone to buy.
If you get them to buy something else
or buy more from you,
that's just a meta move
because we're already there.
Then you've got GOATs.
GOATs are going to be your clients who do
really well, and basically, with those
GOATs,
you can reuse their transformations
or their testimonials to
get more views, which is okay.
Another thing you do with the GOATs
is get them
or their story to potentially get you some
leads. "Hey, this is Ryan.
He just doubled his revenue.
I've created an action plan
that golf instructors can
do.
Pop in your email address," whatever it
is.
Another thing that I would very much do
with the GOATs is actually use them in
emails.
This is probably my favorite place to put
GOATs is in emails.
"Hey, this is John,
reached doubled his revenue." The GOATs
therefore will have a
trickle-down effect on the amount of
people that buy,
and that's your very basic
funnel. Now, here's the thing
that I'm trying to say.
Anyone that tells you there
is a certain amount of views
or a certain amount of
clicks or a certain amount of whatever to
get a sale is talking shit, and they're
completely fucking lying to you.
And I can prove it.
So people will say to me, "James,
what's a good click-through rate?
What's a good amount of sign-ups from lead
magnet? What's a good amount of views?
What's a good amount of it?" I can't give
you that because first of all, from a
business perspective,
all of you do very different businesses.
Now, a GLB coach, breathwork coach,
meditation coach, very different.
Then there's you.
You might have different levels of
authority.
You might even have different things like
how good-looking you are.
Being good-looking
is a fucking meta hack for...
Think about all the dudes that
are in better shape than me
that sold more programs
or workouts or whatever because they're in
better shape, genetics, whatever.
You might not even have a trustworthy
face.
Then you've got your skill,
your communication, your language.
If you speak Slovenian,
your total addressable market
is a lot smaller than someone
that speaks Australian, English, American,
whatever.
So then you've got the type of content you
put out, you've got the type of emails
you write, you've got your offer,
you've got your price point.
And again, your price point
is going to be indicative of where you're
at in the
market. If you're new to training
and your offer is cheaper,
it might be easier for
people to buy it than otherwise. There
are so many variables in place that
it is just unprofessional to tell people
there is a certain amount of numbers that
equate a certain amount of outcome.
I would say to the majority of you,
a 1% conversion is good. Is it great?
No. But just aim for it. Click-throughs,
don't think it's that important.
Open rates, 50%, 60% would be nice,
but again, open rates, a lot of
people's browsers
are now opening the email to scan it for
different harsh
spamware, phishing, whatever.
Not to mention, again,
they click the links in your
emails. So I don't really think
that data is as accurate as a lot of
people would make out.
How do you turn viewers into buyers?
Good question.
The first thing is going to be time.
Don't know about you,
but I love to compare this to dating.
Now, some people, men especially,
seem to think that chicks aren't horny.
I think that women can be hornier than men
a lot of the time.
But the issue is women have got standards,
but also, a lot of the
time, they just want to make sure
that the dude is right for them,
and they don't
want to make a mistake.
You could argue that the mistake of having
a one-night
stand for women is much worse than for
men.
So women have to be very careful.
And it's actually very similar to the
buyer's
market, where people
are quite hesitant to make a purchase.
Men and wives very differently.
So to do so,
if you go up to a woman in a bar and
go,
"Can I have a blowjob?" She's probably
going to say no.
Say, "Can I come home with you
and have sex with you?" Probably say no.
But if you go through the right steps
first, she could become your wife.
Let's just make up some numbers here.
I reckon someone's going to need to watch
between five and 25 pieces of content
to be red hot. Over 25,
they're probably just going to be a
lurker, which is fine.
Any less than five,
they haven't seen you enough.
When it comes to the data,
you would want their email address,
and I reckon you
would want them to read between 10
and 60 emails.
The reason I say 60 is I would say that
is 20, but there's so many times that
people have been like, "Okay,
been reading your emails for a year.
I'm in." The visits,
they're probably going to make three to
seven visits to your
website,
and they're just going to get there,
and there's going to be things that,
"Oh, I really wanted to join today,
but payday, I'm going to wait.
I'm going to put it off." That's why I
hate it when people send traffic straight
to
a website because they're insinuating
they're going to buy first time.
For instance, Iron Neck.
I use this to train my neck.
I reckon I went to the website maybe five
times and left without purchasing because
I was like, "Do I really need that? No,
I've got it." You bet I watched a lot of
fucking YouTube about the GT3 before I
bought it. Same with the sauna.
Probably went on this website two
or three times before I got it. Big up,
Revive.
Then when you buy,
probably going to experience a 5% refund
rate
maximum. If you're getting more than 5%,
you have a problem.
Retention depends on products,
depends on offer.
GOATs depends on offer,
depends on product type.
One of the questions you might be thinking
is how do I grow an email list with
content?
Now I've actually made a lead magnet
course, which is completely free.
You know people say it's free,
and it's not free. It is actually free.
There's going to be a link to
that in the description,
just because I don't think
we have the amount of time
or you don't have the amount of time for
me to go
through that in detail.
That will go through different types of
lead magnets,
what's working, what isn't.
Because I'm currently with what?
Thousand fitness businesses now.
100,000 messages.
30,000 of them are mine.
I've seen a lot of good lead magnets
and a lot of bad lead
magnets. So download that.
That's going to be your best bet.
Okay, we'll go upstairs for the last part.
So you've probably got four questions
left, and one of which
is do you need a sales
page? And a sales page is something
that looks like this.
Now, I think that the realm
and the time of sales calls is dying.
I think that people needed information
from a call back in the day, and for some
high-ticket offers,
you might still need it.
But I think that you should have a menu
that you can send people to so they can
peruse your offer. Now, again,
there's going to be a link to this
high-converting landing page. Also,
if you do download this from this video,
I've
put in an AI prompt
that we've been using inside the
mentorship, where in essence,
it's a form you fill out in quite a bit of
detail And it helps populate
using Claude,
or you can put it in other AIs,
how your landing page should look,
and it gives you loads of different
options for the copy,
which has saved people a
lot of time and effort. But better yet,
we've seen some conversion rates jump from
1% to 3%, which doesn't sound like a lot,
but it's two-thirds more money for no
extra work. Because
if you get your landing page right,
or you get to optimize
it to the point that it makes it easy for
people to decide to buy your stuff, you
don't have to do any more work in the
process above it.
You are getting more money from the exact
same amount of work, which is a very
exciting prospect for people everywhere.
So you need a title
which explains what you do with some kind
of promise.
You then need to have a subheading,
which underneath gives context to that.
So you can go super bold with this,
and then you might actually give a bit
more
nuance into that. I think a VSL
is a very good idea, a video sales letter.
If you go to any of my pages,
it'd be me explaining why you should buy
the product.
And then there's some other structures
that are very important when it comes to
pricing, offer. For instance,
one big mistake that I see people make is
personal trainers trying to combine their
in-person and online training services
into the same sales page. Now,
appreciate the hustle, but how many people
that are right for your online coaching
live within five kilometers of your gym?
So let's just think.
The whole internet can join your online
program with the skill
set that you've got. But the second
that you put in person there as well,
they've
got to live within five kilometers,
have a membership at your gym.
They then have to be able to be free at
the times you're working, which may not be
possible.
And they would then have to come in,
and you would have to have that slot
free.
Some people might only have lunchtimes
or might only be able to do mornings
or whatever it is.
It just muddies the waters.
Another thing is I
was working with a physio recently who had
his online and
in-person offers on the same page.
And the issue is there
that he has pricing where you can see him
in person and work
online. But the issue is,
if I'm looking for an online person,
and let's say you
live in Canada,
when I see all these in-person offers,
I'm starting to think I'm
missing out. Oh, if I lived in Canada,
I could go see this lady in person and do
the online. I'm only getting the online.
So I've kind of made the offer look worse.
So I think you should only ever push for
online with your sales pages and offers.
If someone does see, oh,
you live in Tunbridge Wells,
I'm only two minutes away.
Can I come see you in person? Cool.
But let's aim for everything online,
because if
you do the maths between the amount of
people that live within 5 kilometers of
you
versus the entire fucking planet,
there are a lot more people there.
So let's go for that. Sorry
if you keep seeing me look down.
I'm importing from my DJI Pocket Osmo.
The Osmo4 is about to come out, ladies
and gentlemen.
I've already pre-ordered mine.
That'll be cool. Look forward to that.
Because what I do is I'm uploading my
files to
Declan as we're speaking.
So he's just had two weeks off work.
So I need to fucking put him to it.
You know what I mean? Where was I?
Important question.
How much do you charge?
Very important question.
So again, when you get into the industry,
pick whatever.
And again,
we're going to use demand to work our way
up.
If people aren't paying your rate,
you're too expensive.
If they are paying it and you're full,
you're too cheap.
That's how to work it off.
When it comes to online,
I think a good starting point
is to charge people per week
what you used to charge for an hour.
Some people like to charge monthly,
which is fine. I get it.
Or 12-week blocks.
But just think about the barriers to
entry.
I guarantee the people
that watch this video
that join the mentorship will join on
a split pay. It's not
that they don't have the money.
They just don't want to give it to me all
at once, which is fine.
That's just cash flow, right?
So question one, are you a good coach?
Yes.
Question two,
if people do your online program,
will they love it? Yes.
So would you take them on,
on a weekly rolling basis? If not,
why not?
What insecurity is those?
And stop being insecure.
You're just worried they're going to join
for a couple of weeks then leave.
And if you're not very good
or they're not very good for the program,
that's fine.
And let me tell you this. Someone
that stays with you for three weeks
and bails
probably won't want their money back.
But someone that pays you for 12 weeks up
front and struggles in week two will.
And if you don't give them the money back,
you're going to have a very unhappy
customer that chats shit about your
program.
So I think there are many benefits to
charging weekly.
And also,
I just think it's quite nice to have a hot
poker up the ass to keep you
accountable to the fact
that you need to keep delivering
or they're going to fuck
off. If I said to you,
you can buy five years of servicing for
your car right now
today,
and it's only 10% cheaper than paying for
the service every time the car
goes in. What would you say? Exactly.
Next question is how do you deliver your
service? There are lots of good apps.
There's Everfit, there's Trainer.
There's so much.
I would recommend that you look at those.
Same with email marketing platforms.
I don't have an allegiance to any yet,
but my coach that I use, my jujitsu S&C
coach, gives me an Excel spreadsheet.
And I'm happy because I just want my
fucking program written for me.
I don't care about apps and logging in
and check-ins.
And again, that's another thing.
So many of you are doing check-ins.
They don't want to do them.
You don't want to do them,
and they don't want to do them.
So many of you are doing check-ins with
your clients. They don't enjoy it.
You don't enjoy it. No one enjoys it.
What are you doing?
And if neither of you are enjoying it,
but you go,
"It's critical." Do one a month.
Do one in fucking two months.
Go to all your clients and go, "Hey,
check-ins no
longer exist. If you want one, message me.
We'll have a chat for 15 minutes." Watch
the amount of work that you're spending
having needless fucking chats with your
clients disappear.
And if someone needs a fucking check-in
every week, you ask yourself,
is this worth
it?
Because Tracey wants a check-in every week
and she's paying the same as Steve,
but doesn't want to fucking talk to me,
and Steve's actually getting better
results.
You might have to let one of them go
or just tell them how it is.
I do not do phone calls, and to me,
a check-in sounds like a phone call.
Or if they want to do it,
charge them hundreds
and do the hour happily.
How much support are people going to get
on your program depends on how much you're
charging and what level of support they
want to get.
So for instance, in my mentorship,
daily Discord, because I would much rather
someone goes, "Hey,
what color should I have my font on my
landing?" Black and
white, brother.
I've just saved this guy 2.5% conversions
by giving him a
snappy little response.
Or someone asked me, "Hey,
this video bombed.
Can you tell me why?" I watch it and I go,
"Mate, the first 10 seconds, it's
awful." They go,
"What about the rest?" I go,
"What do you mean, what about the
rest? No one made it past 10 seconds,
brother." Then that feedback gets to that
person.
I've given them 10 seconds of my time,
probably like a minute.
But now they get to go away
and work on their hooks better.
That's the communication style.
That's why I only charge $3,500.
The reason I do that is, yes,
I'm getting paid. I'm living good.
But at the same time,
they're going to see a return on
investment on that in two to
three months.
And they're there for thereafter.
I've got several clients who now do 100K a
month every month.
Some of them have invested in Nu Tonic.
Sam, Ryan, big up.
This now partially belongs to you brothers
and my boy Freddy.
The last question you're probably thinking
is, do you need to hire people?
At this stage, no. And if you
are going to hire someone, hire me,
because the
insight and the snappy responses I give in
the Discord will do more for your
business than some twat you've just--
Think about this.
If you wanted to hire someone with no
experience,
fresh out of uni with a fucking
MBA, whatever that is.
I don't know what an MBA is.
Help me in the comments.
They're going to cost you tens of
thousands a year. For what? For what?
So yeah, I'm cheaper. I'm better.
So give me your money.
So again,
there's going to be some free resources,
which I spoke about before.
The two main offers are this,
PT Starter Kit, Business Mentorship.
Here you go.
My email address is james@nutonic.com.
If you buy the PT Starter Kit
and don't fucking love it
and see the benefit to your
business, email me.
I'll send you the fucking money back.
How's that? Bash.
All right, I feel good.
I've just saved you fuckloads of mistakes
that you were
probably going to make in your fitness
business.
Out of respect, all I'm asking is
that you… I was going to say give me
money.
I don't care.
If you're one of the 90% of people that's
never going to buy my stuff
and you have questions,
just ask them below.
I don't bite,
and I'm more than happy to respond.
If you are ready to absorb more of my
content, YouTube actually recommends this
video here.
Says it's going to be perfect for you.
Me, I've got to go babysit my son.
Apparently, it's not babysitting
if it's your
own kid, as my fiancée keeps telling me,
but that's what I'm doing. So I'm off.
Love you lots. Bye bye.